Hi, in this lesson I will go through the ask mode you'll show how to work with it, what
the most popular use cases for ask mode and you'll show you some prompt examples on practice.
So, ask mode is read only mode for learning and explanations.
You can choose it as the ask mode right here.
Be careful because by default cursor set agent mode, as default mode and if you want to
use ask mode every time or any other mode you even need to select it manually.
Or you can of course change it in settings and show you how to do it in previous lesson.
So, you can use this mode to ask questions about your whole code base or some technology
concepts.
It's useful for getting a better understanding of your code base without making any changes.
It's also good for bridge storming ideas or getting help with some coding tasks.
So, let's go through some use cases in details and understanding better your code base.
You can ask for example what this method or what this book means or what it does in component
why it's needed.
So, you can also ask to explain how this function works or it can help you to learn the
whole code base for example.
You can also use it for bridge storming ideas.
You don't know how to name variable or method you can ask or sort to give you ideas how
to name it.
It's the most popular use case I do.
You can also ask what test cases you can cover for this component.
If you know have idea or if you want to for example write more test cases so it can help
you.
How to for example write some code using CSS, how to improve performance of your application.
This might be complex because we're not always know what we used wrongly and I can help
us to identify these problems.
We can ask some ideas how to implement some functionality for example storage or pagination
of filtering help with coding tasks.
Same to the last point.
So, we can ask how to implement for example this functionality some search functionality
for this component give me few ideas give me a plan to tell it to step by step how I can
do it.
You can also ask how to handle some events for example if you use a new library.
You can ask question about this library for example what props you can pass to the component
or for example if you want to implement pagination okay what props you need to pass to
the pagination component we shall require it for example console can help you.
Let's back to our editor and I will show you some interface options.
If you click on ask mode and click on edit icon right here you'll see few options you can
choose.
You can set some specific model and to be set only for the ask mode so you can if you
toggle off auto you can choose any other model but I prefer to use auto I have some ask
questions and you can also set some shortcut how you can quickly switch to the ask mode.
If you click on it you need to press press your keys for example comment plus a and you
want to see this keys right here and if you click outside you will see this keys will
be set yeah like and then you can quickly switch between different modes using the key
combinations but be aware of some times if you want to switch you it won't work because
you need to click outside and then you will be able to switch again so let's check the
last option storage code base it's a really nice option which helps you storage answer
questions about all your code base let me show you how it works if I disable this option
I will close all the file remove files from a context and then you want to ask what
currency is my application support so it should go through all the files and check it
what currency is my support you see it provide me only the name of the files in try to guess
what currency is it good support but he really don't know when ask us to share so it doesn't
have access to the code base to search it so let me enable this option I will create a new
chat and ask same question what currency is my application support and you don't see it provided
me the least of exact currencies we support right here oh we can use it it's really useful
if you want to quickly learn and don't find manually all the files okay let me show you
some examples for example we can ask how to implement functionality imagine we want to
take all the conversions in our class like we want to log every operation we do maybe
you ask how to implement history for currency conversions you need to decide where to store
history modify the conversion logic for example it suggests me to create a new function
we can make a bigger safe conversion to history he store it in local storey shivin
and we'll store amount from two result and even date oh and drive and disk with the
history okay and optionally we can clear the history if you want okay how we can implement
we can visually copy basic manually we have an option applied to the file is the file
is opened yeah we click apply and we see it providing you a function right here but I don't
want to implement it like this I will reject it I will reject everything and we'll ask
follow up question and make it inside the class you see we need to provide more context
because it's sometimes don't fully understand what we want or I want to really it be
is a class functionality yeah let's wait a bit is generating something
let's review to this time the rest functionality he provide us okay yes it did it yeah it moved
all the methods for the class also added some examples how to use it so to apply it we
can click on apply if you apply to a code base and this can go through all the places
right here to check what the differences we can reject or accept it for example we can
also use icons right here to accept or reject it we can collapse it yeah if you want to
focus on the reading the text for example instructions what options we have we have option
to copy and paste it later for example for some other file if for example if you reject
it like let's click reject we have option to wrap by it we also see the code difference
right here we have three dots functionality we can click show code we can click show
div to see what lines will be removed and what lines will be added but also we have option
to wrap by and it will wrap right right here we can accept one by one or we can click
accept all and you also see all the files edited right here I will click accept all and
now it's applied so this is everything I want to show you about ask mode and see you
in the next lesson